the Bible says then certain of the
scribes and of the Pharisees answered
saying master we would see a sign from
thee but he answered and said unto them
an evil and adulterous generation
seeketh after a sign and there shall no
sign be given to it but the sign of the
Prophet Jonas pause for a second Jesus
here speaking says an evil and
adulterous generation seeks a sign is
that a good thing or a bad things that
sound like Jesus is saying something
that is good or something that is bad
right an evil and adulterous generation
seeks after a sign and yet the Bible
continues on because Jesus says that
they will actually receive a sign that
they actually do receive a sign and that
sign according to verse 39 is the sign
of the prophet Jonah verse 44 s Jonah
was three days and three nights in the
whales belly so shall the Son of Man be
three days and three nights in the heart
of the earth the men of Nineveh shall
rise up in judgment with this generation
and shall condemn it because they
repented at the preaching of Jonah and
behold a greater than Jonah is here the
Queen of the South shall rise up in
judgment with this generation and shall
condemn it for she came from the
uttermost parts of the earth to hear the
wisdom of Solomon and behold a greater
than Solomon is here Jesus does not draw
these two stories just out of a hat
somewhere he speaks of the story of
Jonah and then he speaks of the story of
the Queen of the south anyone know who
that is
the Queen of Sheba so on one hand he is
addressing the story of Jonah and his
Jurnee here's what everyone his journey
to where Nineveh and then on the other
hand he addresses the Queen of Sheba and
her journey somewhere now who knows
where she bowing where the Queen of
Sheba went where did she go
who does she go to see she went to see
Solomon and what city did she go to
Jerusalem very good
so here Jesus takes two stories two
journeys one of Jonah to Nineveh one of
the Queen of Sheba to Jerusalem and he
couples these stories together and
beloved there's a reason why he does
this want you to notice this with me the
sign that Jesus said would be given to
the evil and adulterous generation how
many of you would probably agree with me
that we are living in an evil and
adulterous generation yeah and even
though Jesus when he was speaking was
speaking specifically of a generation
that he was in because they were the
generation that would receive this sign
of Jonah three days and three nights in
the in the belly of the fish we are
still in an evil and adulterous
generation and I want to suggest to you
that the sign is still the same sign the
sign for this generation this evil and
adulterous generation is the same sign
that it was when Jesus spoke at almost
2,000 years ago it is still the death
burial and resurrection of Jesus Christ
the greatest sign we can give to an evil
and adulterous generation is listen
carefully it is not the prophecy of
revelation 13 or Daniel 7 or any of
those other prophecies the greatest sign
that we can give to an evil and
adulterous generation to lead them to
believe and be prepared for the coming
of Jesus is the death burial and
resurrection of Jesus Christ in fact I
believe that this sign is
is so great that all our the signs point
to this sign all other signs given in
the Bible is given so that we may
believe that Jesus died was buried and
resurrected again as the scripture says
Paul in 1st Corinthians chapter 1 verse
22 writes this for the Jews require a
sign and the Greeks seek after wisdom
but we preach Christ Watts crucified
unto the Jews a stumbling-block and
foolishness or and unto the Greeks
foolishness but unto them which are
called both Jews and Greeks Christ the
power and wisdom of God the Bible tells
us here that Christ crucified Christ
dead buried and resurrected is the
wisdom of God Paul said there is nothing
greater than the preaching of this
message Christ and him crucified it is
the wisdom of God notice with me John
chapter 14 verse 29 you will go through
these verses rapidly and then we're
going to go over to the Book of Jonah
but I want you to notice with me John
chapter 14 verse 29 and 30 Jesus
speaking here says and now I have told
you before it come to pass that when it
come to pass you might want believe
hereafter I will not talk much with you
for the prince of this world cometh and
has nothing in me now what was Jesus
talking about here what did he mean when
he said hereafter I will not talk with
you much what was about to happen to him
he was about to be killed he was about
to be crucified
but Jesus connects prophecy with that
very thing he says behold I tell you
before we come to pass that when it
comes to pass
you might believe what that I am he let
me suggest to you that all the
prophecies of Daniel and all the
prophecies of Revelation are geared
towards one thing for us to believe that
Jesus died was buried and rose again the
third day because that is the greatest
sign see all these other prophecies are
given to us so that we can believe God
amen God says I want you to believe me
believe what believe that my son came
died and rose again well why would I
believe that well let me give you
prophecy to show you that what I say is
true so as you see prophecies unfold it
is designed to strengthen our
understanding and our belief that Jesus
Christ died was buried and rose again
prophecy strengthens our faith in the
death burial and resurrection of Jesus
Christ